니콜라스 케이지
윈드토커
아담 비치
로저 윌리
크리스챤 슬레이터
감독 오우삼
찰리!
Charlie!
자네도 탈 줄은 몰랐어
I wasn't so sure you'd be on the bus.
자네만 최고가 아니란 걸
손수 보여주려고 탔네
Didn't want your white brothers
thinking you were the best we had.
"솔로몬 제도, 1943년"
SOLOMON ISLANDS
조심해!
Watch out!
내 손!
My hand!
젠장!
Goddamn!
탄약이 떨어져서
철수해야 해요
We're running out of ammo.
We gotta get out of here.
움직여!
Move!
힘내!
Come on!
어서, 할 수 있다!
Come on, you can do it! Come on!
탄약이 없습니다!
We got nothin', Enders!
We're out of ammo!
인명 손실이 큽니다
여길 뜨는 게 상책이에요!
Joe... Nobody else needs to die.
We can go! We can get outta here!
우린 명령에 산다!
We got orders!
여길 사수하라는
명령에 따라야 돼!
They told us to hold the position!
And that's what we're gonna do!
정신들 차리고
모두 사격 위치로!
Get up, marine!
Hold the goddamn position!
이리 와!
Come on!
엎드려!
Get down!
토미!
Tommy.
이 개자식들!
Goddamn you!
안 돼!
Oh, no! No!
- 빌!
- 총알이 없어요
- Bill!
- I'm out.
이리 와!
Come on! Come on!
조 앤더스,
이 망할 자식!
Goddamn you, Joe Enders.
안 돼!
No... No!
No!
오른손 들고 복창!
Raise your right hand.
- 나, 다음엔 본인 이름
- 나, 벤 야지는...
- I... State your full name...
- I, Ben Yahzee...
캘리포니아 주, 팬들톤 막사
CAMP PENDLETON, CALIFORNIA
미국의 헌법을 충실히
수호할 것을 선언합니다
..do solemnly swear to support and
defend the constitution of the US...
..against all enemies,
foreign and domestic...
국내외를 막론하고
모든 적에 대해...
..against all enemies,
foreign and domestic...
일본 탱크의
암호는 무엇인가?
Jap Ha-Go. Who can give me
the code word for "tank"?
암호통신병
지망생들이 뭐 이래
Come on. You boys
wanna be codetalkers.
머리 좀 굴려 봐
Show me some brains. Think!
탱크를 뭐라 할까?
What do we call a tank?
Chay-da-gahi.
거북이, 좋다
Tortoise. Good.
대포에 대한 암호는?
Artillery. Code word?
와잇홀스, 말해 봐
In code. Private Whitehorse.
Be-al-doh-tso-lani?
아주 좋아
Very good.
일본공군 제로기는?
Japanese Zero. Code word?
"카네오헤만 미 해군 병원,
1943년"
KANEOHE BAY US NAVAL HOSPITAL
여길 뜨는 게 상책이에요!
We can go! We can get outta here!
여길 사수해야 한다!
They told us to hold the position!
날씨가 좋죠?
Nice day, huh?
조?
Joe?
Joe.
제 말 못 들었죠?
Didn't hear a word, did you?
미인이 말을 걸면
가끔 그래요
That's what happens to a man
when he's talking to a beautiful woman.
제 입술을 안 읽어서겠죠
It happens when you're
not watching my lips, Joe.
잘 봐요
Watch this.
이 상태로 어떻게 퇴원해요?
You're a mess, Joe.
You're not fooling anybody.
그 말은 저 친구한테 해요
No, Rita. He's a mess.
난 호전되고 있소
I'm getting better every day.
고막에 구멍이 나서
균형 잡기가 힘들어요
You got a perforated eardrum, Enders.
Your equilibrium's all screwy.
일어서기라도 해야
전장에 나가죠
You can't go back to war
if you can't stand up.
가자, 해병들
전투가 기다리고 있다
Let's go, marines. This war
ain't gonna wait forever. Let's go.
Joe...
그냥 여기 계시면 안 돼요?
Why don't you just stay here, Joe?
친구도 사귀었잖아요
Somebody's gotta keep
the WAVES company.
도와줄 거요, 말 거요?
Are you gonna help me or not?
"난청"
좋아졌군
Marked improvement.
왼쪽 귀가 더 나빴나?
And his left ear is the worse of the two?
놀랍네요
It's... amazing.
TBX가 TBY보다 한 수 위다
TBY hasn't got the range of the TBX.
메시지를 지휘소로 전할 때
So you may need a relay to get
your transmission to command post.
관건은 극한 상황 속에서의
속도와 정확도다
But what it really comes down to
is speed and accuracy under pressure.
녹취 시작
Transcribe now.
빅터, 여긴 X-ray
Victor, Victor. This is X-ray. Over.
젠장!
불이 난 상황이다!
Damn it! We got a unit under fire!
대원들이 죽어가고 있어!
We're losing men.
이걸 해독하도록
I need this message decrypted.
"소방 지원 바람
목표물은 1-1-9 지점"
"Request fire support. We have target
at one-one-niner, Baker one-five."
"토치카 내 기관총, 난사"
"Pillbox with heavy machine gun.
Fire at will."
초심자의 행운이지
Beginner's luck.
들어가시죠
You're up, mac.
- 앤더스 하사관입니다
- 쉬어
- Corporal Enders reporting, sir.
- At ease.
이력이 대단하더군, 하사
You've done well as a marine, Corporal.
입대 전엔 망나니였더군
Better than you did as a civilian.
오토바이 강탈에
고등학교 퇴학
Stole a motorbike, crashed it.
Got kicked out of high school.
크리스핀 오도넬 신부
폭행 및 구타?
Assault and battery...
on one Father Crispin O'Donnell?
신부님을?
A priest?
아키비숍 키넌 고교의
교감이자 규율 담당이셨죠
Assistant principal at Archbishop Keenan
High School, sir, and head disciplinarian.
난 공립 출신이지
Public-school boy myself.
신병 땐 문제아였고
Some minor problems in boot.
상하이에서 용맹을 떨친 후
A commendation for valor in Shanghai.
솔로몬 제도에서
큰 공을 세웠군
And you made a hell of a stand
on the Solomons.
거기가 좀 치열했지?
Tough bit of business there, huh?
그렇습니다
Pretty tough, sir.
준비는 단단히 했겠지?
But you're prepared
to jump right back into it?
예, 그렇습니다
Yes, sir. Very much so.
그렇군
Very much so.
그러니까...
Well...
일본군은 우리 암호를
꽤 잘 해독해 왔네
The Japs have pretty much busted
every code we've thrown at 'em, Corporal.
자네 부하들도
그 때문에 희생당했고
You men on the Solomons
were lost to a broken code.
솔로몬 제도에서
인디언들을 못 봤나?
Tell me something. You ever
run into any Indians on the Solomons?
- 인디언이라뇨?
- 나바호족 말야
- Indians, sir?
- Navajo, to be exact.
그들 언어로
새 암호를 개발해냈네
The Corps has developed a new code
based on their language.
워낙 중요한 사안이라
It's had quite an impact.
해병대가 암호 보호에
본격적으로 나서기로 했지
So much so the navy have decided
to go to great lengths to protect it.
때문에 자네가 필요해
That's why you're here.
자네 임무는 나바호 파트너를
보호하는 걸세
You're to pair with one of them,
keep his ass safe.
최선을 다해 파트너를 지키게
Your job is to keep him alive
so he can do his job.
전 일본군 살상이 전문입니다
Begging the major's pardon, but I believe
I'd best serve the Corps killing Japs,
누구 뒤치다꺼리는 싫습니다
not baby-sitting some Indian.
자네를 이 일에 적임자로 본 건
Enders, we didn't pick
your name out of a hat.
뛰어난 해병이기 때문이네
We need good marines.
그래서 자넬 부른 거고
That's why you're standing here.
보게나
Take a look.
나바호족일세
It's a Navajo. Or it was.
암호를 해독하려던
일본군들 짓이지
Tortured to death by Japanese
intelligence trying to bust our code.
그가 불려고 했어도
그럴 수가 없었네
Fortunately, he couldn't help them
even if he wanted to.
- 왜죠?
- 순수 나바호족이었거든
- Sir?
- Man's a Navajo, not a codetalker.
코드는 그들 언어로
만들어진 걸세
Code's based on their language,
but it is still a code.
괜한 민간인만 희생된 거지
Tojo would like nothing more
than to catch a live one.
자네가 승낙하기 전엔
이 방을 나갈 수 없네
What I'm about to tell you, Corporal,
cannot leave this room.
암호 통신병이 일본군
손에 들어가면 끝장이야
Under no circumstances can you allow
your codetalker to fall into enemy hands.
암호를 보호하는 게
자네 임무네
Your mission is to protect the code...
무슨 수를 써서라도
at all costs.
알아들었나?
You understand me?
예, 알겠습니다
Yes, sir, I do.
좋아
Good.
축하하네
이제부터 중사일세
Congratulations. You just made sergeant.
손을 쭉 뻗어
Keep those hands vertical.
잘 했다
Way to go, marine.
포티노, 대신 봐줘
Fortino, take over.
Hey... That was you, right,
sitting in front of the major's office?
소령님 사무실
대기실에서 봤죠?
피트 핸더슨입니다
Yeah. Listen, I'm Pete Henderson.
'옥스'라고 불리죠
특별한 건 없고
They call me Ox.
Not cos of my big muscles or anything.
캘리포니아 옥스나드
출신이라서요
I'm from Oxnard, California.
Just north of Hollywood a ways.
JASCO 일원이죠?
So you're with JASCO too, huh?
제 2 합동 공격
통신대가 어디죠?
Hey, know where we might find
2nd Joint Assault Signal?
쥐뿔도 모르겠는데
No fuckin' idea, mac.
눈물 나게 고맙군
Thanks. Thanks a bunch.
백인들을 떼거지로
보는 건 처음이야
I've never seen so many white men.
그건 저쪽도 피차일반일 걸
They've never seen so many Navajo.
보아하니 몸이
근질근질 한가 본데
Looks to me like you got to see
a little action there.
나도 그래요
Me too.
망할 일본 놈들,
엉덩짝에 한 방 먹었죠
Jap sons of bitches
shot me right in the ass.
상상이 가요?
꼼짝 못하겠더라고요
You believe that shit?
I wasn't running or nothin'.
JASCO 임무가 혹시
나바호 암호병과 관련 있나요?
So, your duty with JASCO have anything
to do with these Navajo radiomen?
그건 기밀이네
I'm not at liberty to say.
계급장이 늘었네요
나도 그런데
I see you got a new stripe there. Me too.
말씀 못하는 걸로 봐선
나랑 같은 처지 같은데
So I'm guessing the orders you can't tell
me are the same orders I can't tell you.
무시무시하지 않나요?
Hell of a thing, huh?
해병대에 민주적인 거라곤 없지
Ain't a democracy, Sergeant.
It's the marines.
Yeah.
정상인들 같은데요
They look pretty normal, I guess.
특수 분장이라도 기대했나?
Expecting them to wear war paint?
가서 인사라도 나눠야겠어요
좀 어리둥절해 보이네요
Maybe we ought to go introduce
ourselves. They look a little lost to me.
Henderson.
과잉 친절은 금물일세
I wouldn't get too friendly.
차렷!
How!
장난이다, 난 옥스
Just kiddin'. I'm Ox.
전 와잇홀스고
Whitehorse.
여긴 벤 야지 입니다
This is Yahzee. Ben.
- 다음!
- 이게 뭐야
- Next.
- Beautiful. Beautiful.
눈감고 먹으면 돼, 다음?
Close your eyes. It'll taste better.
Who's next?
좀 끼어도 될까요?
Mind if I join you?
벤 야지예요
중사님 파트너 입니다
I'm Ben Yahzee.
Guess the Corps paired us up.
안녕하세요?
How you doin'?
내 시야를 가리지 마
You're blocking my view.
죄송합니다
Oh, sorry.
이 거지 같은 음식은 뭐죠?
What do they call this crap anyway?
그냥 '음식'이라고 하지
Marines call it chow.
선전 효과를 노린 거군요
Well, there's a propaganda effort.
죄송해요
제 걸 드세요
Sorry. You can have mine.
이런!
Shit.
이름이 뭐라 했지, 사병?
What'd you say your name was again,
Private?
It's Yahzee. Ben Yahzee.
이거 들어
Hold this.
젠장!
Shit.
백인 파트너는 어때?
How's your white man?
굶주렸어
Hungry.
2개 더 걸고...
I'm in for a couple more.
아들한테 쓰나?
You writing to your son?
내 안부도 전해 줘
Tell him I say hello.
영국엔 카우보이 원 페어
Pair of cowboys for Big E.
- 그리스엔 스트레이트
- 웃기지 말라 그러셔
- Possible straight for the Greek.
- Possible thumb up the Greek's ass.
꼬마는 2 원 페어
훌륭해
Oh, a pair of twos for the kid.
Lookin' good.
- Oh, come on!
- Now there's a bold move.
세게 나가시네
좋았어
All right.
OK... Oh, another mess
for the Sunshine State.
선샤인 주는 또 망했군
- 내가 미워요?
- 돈만 따면 돼
- What, are you mad at me?
- Just want your money.
Hey! Look at that. A trio of nines. Pretty.
이거 봐
9 트리플이야
- 제대로 섞었어요?
- 당연하지
- You shuffle that deck?
- I certainly did.
2개 더 올리고
Nines bets. I'll raise it two bits.
콜
Call.
뒤집어쓰게 생겼군
We all got thumbs up our asses.
정보부에 있는 친구 말이
곧 출격이 있을 거래
You won't for much longer. I got a buddy
in Intel that says we ship out in a week.
다음 주면 벌써 한 달째야
I been hearing "next week" for a month.
정보부에 친구가 있다니 의외인데
I didn't know you knew
anybody in intelligence, Harri.
내년에 출격해도
난 상관없어
Next year'd be all right with me.
울 준비들 하시고
봐, 풀 하우스야
Gentlemen, read 'em and weep.
Look at that. Nines and fours.
긁어가겠군
Full boat, baby.
킹 카우보이
확인들 해
Cowboys over queens. Read 'em and die.
이런, 세상에!
Oh, Jesus!
Ouch. Ouch.
- 그만 빠질래
- 편지질이나 해야지
- Fuck it. I'm out.
- Yeah. I'm gonna go write the missus.
한눈이라도 팔면 안 되니까
God knows what a girl will do
without reassurance.
다 잃었어
Son of a bitch.
자리가 두 개 났는데
낄 거야?
Hey, looks like we got a coupla seats
opening up. You wanna come join us?
진담이에요?
Are you serious?
인디언 포커?
그건 어떻게 하더라?
What, injun poker?
Hey, how do you boys do that again?
카드를 머리에 얹고
꼭 바보 같이...
Card on the head,
only fool can't see it is you.
낄 거야, 말 거야?
You want to come on over, or what?
합니다
Cut me in.
피어리 크로스, 하이로우,
호거스도 좋지...
I'm thinkin' Fiery Cross, high-low,
hoggers OK, ace plays both ways...
피어리 크로스, 하이로우,
호거스도 좋지...
I'm thinkin' Fiery Cross, high-low,
hoggers OK, ace plays both ways...
겁먹을 필요 없어
Hey, don't let him scare you.
그래봤자 시간과
돈 낭비는 같으니까
If you've ever played a high-low game, it's
like any other. Waste of time and money.
판돈 찔러, 추장
Well, ante up... Chief.
어떻게 알았어요?
How'd you know I was a chief?
총알을 얼마나
잘 피했는데요
You must've seen me showering
with my war bonnet.
- 돈 걸어요
- 조개는 안 받아
- Deal 'em up, deal 'em up.
- You know, we don't take wampum here.
좋은데
Beautiful.
다들 모였군
All right, then.
명령이 떨어졌다
Orders finally came through.
출격은 내일 아침이다
We ship out tomorrow morning.
목적지는 사이판 섬
Destination: the island of Saipan,
일본 놈들을 혼내 줄
또 다른 디딤돌이다
which is one of the stepping stones
we gotta take on our road show to Tokyo.
전략적으로
중요한 섬이니 만큼
It's of strategic importance
that we capture this island.
추후엔 활주로와 연료 보급기를
We can get ourselves
an advanced naval base
확보한 해군 기지를
세울 계획이다
and an airstrip to land and refuel B-29's
도쿄와도 가까워 유리하다
and get our bombers
within range of Tokyo.
현재는 일본 령으로
3만 개의 참호 속에 숨어
Now, Saipan is Japanese soil,
and there's 30,000 of 'em dug in.
놈들은 악착같이
덤벼들 것이다
They're gonna fight for every square inch,
놈들 집이니까
우린 그걸 뺏는다
because it's their home,
but we're gonna take it away from 'em!
Yeah! Kill me some Japs!
일본놈들 좀 죽이자!
우린 분대의 최전선에서
We're gonna be in front
of the whole damn division.
눈과 귀가 될 것이다
We're gonna be the eyes and the ears.
적진을 샅샅이 찾아내
We're gonna be
sniffin' out enemy positions,
위치를 알려주면 된다
coordinating the naval gunfire -
지난 4달간
훈련받은 대로다, 알겠나?
exactly what we've been training to do
for the last four months. All right?
본부에서 파견된
신참 통신병이다
Now, we got some new radiomen
from headquarters.
사병 와잇홀스와
There's a Private Whitehorse...
사병 야지다
and Yahzee...
앤더스와 핸더슨 중사는
and a couple of sergeants,
Enders and Henderson,
상부 지시가 정확하다면
who, if I'm understanding
these orders correctly,
이들의 안전을 책임진다
will be covering our Navajos' asses.
조 앤더스,
이 망할 자식!
Goddamn you, Joe Enders!
무슨 일이 있어도
섬을 빼앗아야 한다
..but I'm tellin' you, we'll be steppin'
into our share of the shit nonetheless.
질문 있나?
Any questions?
곧 죽을 것 같군요
Sounds like you're dying.
이걸 써 보세요
These might help get rid of the taste.
샌디애고에서
배타고 올 때 유용했어요
Charlie and l, we both lost it
on the boat ride from San Diego.
뱃멀미가 심한 제겐
Not many bodies of water in Arizona.
꼭 필요한 거죠
Life Savers really helped.
한번 써 보실래요?
You want a Life Saver?
여긴 왜 왔나?
What are you doin' here?
도와주려고요
Just trying to help.
말 돌리지 말고
Not what I meant.
유니폼 입고
뭐 하는지 말입니까?
You mean what am I doing
in this uniform?
제 전쟁이기도 합니다
It's my war too, Sergeant.
조국과 땅과
국민을 위해서 입니다
I'm fighting for my country,
for my land, for my people.
나하곤 목적이 틀리군
Not your people I'm worried about.
전 암호 통신병입니다
Listen, Enders, I'm a codetalker.
1시간 걸리던 걸
2분 만에 해독하죠
It takes me two-and-a-half minutes
to do what used to take an hour.
계급이 높으신 분들도
Now, somebody wearing
a lot more stripes than you
저희를 인정하십니다
thinks that's worth something.
총알이 날아다니는
전쟁터에선 안 그래
Remind me to time you when
you got bullets flying over your head.
왜 그렇게 꼬였어요?
What the hell's wrong with you?
Shave his belly with a rusty razor
Early in the morning!
"몬테주마 성에서"
From the halls of Montezuma
"트리폴리 해변까지"
To the shores of Tripoli
"우린 조국을 지키기 위해"
We will fight our country's battles
"바다와 육지에서 전투를 하지"
On the land and on the sea
"첫 번째는 정의와 자유를 위해"
First to fight for right and freedom
"그리고 우리 명예를 위해"
And to keep our honor clean
"우리는 그 이름도 자랑스러운"
We are proud to claim the title
"미국 해병대"
Of United States Marines
안녕하세요
Hi.
귀는 좀 어때요?
How's that ear?
혹시라도 통증이 오면
복용하세요
Not that you'd ever admit it, but if
it starts aching, take a couple of those.
아침에 전화 주시고요
And call me in the morning.
아침엔 없을 거란 뜻이군요
You're not gonna be here
in the morning, are you?
술도 한번 안사고
출격이네요
Shipping out without even
buying me a drink.
해병대 성격은
대충 아실 텐데요
Ought to be ashamed of yourself,
hustling a... hustling marines.
어떤 독으로 하겠소?
What's your poison?
좀 취하는 걸로
마시고 싶네요
Jeez, might as well go all out.
I'll get a shot of something.
럼으로요
Rum.
바카르디 한 잔 줘
Eddie, give me a shot of Bacardi.
두 잔요
Make that two.
같이 취할 거죠?
May as well join me, huh?
그러죠, 뭐
- Why not?
- OK.
고마워요
Thank you.
전쟁을 위하여
Well... to war.
"일본령 사이판 섬,
1944년 6월 16일"
THE JAPANESE ISLAND OF SAIPAN
JUNE 16, 1944
자, 돌격!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
흩어지라고 해!
Get those men spread out!
찰리, 어서 바삭 붙어!
Charlie, come on, come on, come on!
따라붙어!
Come on, keep up!
그만하고 따라와!
Let's go, let's go, let's go! Come on!
- 나 어때?
- 잘하고 있어
- How am I doin'?
- You're good.
앞으로!
Let's go!
잘 따라붙어
Stay on my ass.
뒤로 따라붙어!
I told you to stay on my ass!
- 엎드려!
- 죽여주마!
- Stay low!
- Get out of there!
돌격!
Go!
가서 구해!
Get him outta there!
구해 줘!
Get me outta here!
- 눈에 띄잖아!
- 빨리 해!
- Hold still, damn it!
- Get him outta there!
다 뒈져라!
You sons of bitches!
포티노! 엄호해!
Fortino! Cover me!
와잇홀스, 엎드려!
Whitehorse, get down!
엎어져!
Get down!
파파스!
Pappas!
위생병!
Corpsman!
헬멧 제대로 써!
위생병!
Helmet goes on your head! Corpsman!
좀 봐줘
Take care of him.
지압하고 있어
Put a hand on this.
탱크!
탱크다!
Tank! Tank! Tank!
뽑았어?
던져!
You ready? Go! Go!
해리건, 한 방 날려!
Harrigan, light it up!
돌격!
제대로 싸워봐!
Let's go, boys! Keep up the fight!
맞았나?
Are you hit? Are you hit?
안 맞았군
괜찮아
You're OK. You're good, you're good.
- 괜찮나?
- 끄떡없습니다
- Are you OK, Chick?
- Still in the hunt, Gunny.
- 해리?
- 전 괜찮습니다
- Harri?
- You ain't gettin' rid of me that easy.
- 몸 낮춰!
- 넬리? 파파스?
- Stay low!
- Nellie? Pappas?
무사합니다
Yeah, we're good.
그리스가 호흡곤란 증셉니다
Greek's predisposed to hyperventilate.
뭐?
What?
흥분하면
숨이 가빠집니다
I can't breathe when I get excited.
데이트도 못하겠군!
Goddamn! Must be hell on your gal!